

# Patricia McPhee

TECHNICAL WRITER
CONTENT DEVELOPER

Broomfield, CO 303.621.6898 hi@patriciamcphee.com

### **About Me**

I have 25 years of experience creating scenario and goal-based content to help IT professionals achieve more with technology. I'm passionate about bringing stale or unusable content back to life by taking the guesswork out of complex technical content.

## **Education**

10/2010 - 05/2012 Kaplan University

BS in Health Science (public and environmental health)

02/1999 - 04/2001 DeVry University Denver

AS Computer Systems (networking and telecommunications)

## **Work Experience**

05/2020 - Pres.

## Senior Content Developer, Contractor

Microsoft/Kforce

Work collaboratively with the Azure VMware Solution core engineering and UX Research teams to develop scenario and goal-based content. Conduct content audits of existing content to identify areas for improvement. Use qualitative and quantitative data to make data-driven decisions.

07/2019 - 06/2021

#### **Freelance**

- Extreme Networks (2020 2021) Reviewed and edited network hardware content for the FIPS program. Wrote shell scripts to automate API content publishing.
- Netdata (2020) Wrote product content for a Linux server performance tool
- **ZPE Systems (2019-2020)** Wrote a marketing campaign eBook on automating the data center. Wrote video scripts, provided the voiceover, and produced how-to videos.
- Wax.io (2019) Contributed to blockchain blog articles.

03/2019 - 06/2019

#### **Technical Writer II**

LivePerson

Wrote SDK and API guides for mobile messaging app.

01/2018 - 01/2019

#### **Technical Writer II**

Microsoft

Worked collaboratively with the Microsoft Edge and Windows networking core teams. Conducted content audits to identify areas for potential improvement. Used qualitative and quantitative data to make data-driven decisions.

07/2017 - 12/2017

#### **Technical Writer, Contractor**

Oculus/Facebook

Developed internal cross-functional workflows and process documentation for a virtual reality R&D environment.

08/2016 - 05/2017

#### Software Technical Writer

**GE Healthcare** 

Worked collaboratively with customers and support to update the outdated installation and upgrade guides. The rework resulted in more successful upgrades and reduced customer support calls.



### **Skills**

**Technical Writing** 

Content Strategy

**UX/UI** Writing

Information Architecture

Video Script Writing

Instructional Design

Markdown

Git/GitHub

Agile/Jira/Azure DevOps

Adobe InDesign

Adobe Premiere Pro

Voiceover

Video Production

MadCap Flare

DITA/XLM

## **Work Experience**

09/2015 - 07/2016

**Technical Writer II** 

Amazon

Wrote internal feature announcements and task-oriented procedure guides for warehouse employees.

03/2015 - 09/2015

**Technical Writer, Contractor** 

**Charter Communications** 

Worked collaboratively with video-on-demand and networking engineers to write standard procedures. Wrote Python scripts for system administration tasks.

01/2014 - 10/2014

**Technical Writer** 

SolidFire, a NetApp company

Wrote release notes, configuration and troubleshooting guides, white papers, and solution briefs for the cloud storage solution.

12/2012 - 12/2013

**Technical Writer, Contractor** 

Sybase/SAP

Wrote installation, configuration, and API guides for a mobile money app.

07/2012 - 01/2013

**Technical Writer, Contractor** 

CarpeDatum

Wrote design specifications and instructor-led training guides for enterprise planning and budgeting software.

08/2011 - 07/2012

**Technical Writer, Contractor** 

Level 3 Communications, a CenturyLink company

Wrote fiber optic provisioning procedures for field technicians.

### **Achievements**

- Wrote shell scripts to automate API content publishing.
- Built custom MadCap Flare authoring environment for GE Healthcare, Amazon, and SolidFire. Converted legacy documentation created in Microsoft Word to maximize content reuse and reduce the cost of creating, managing, and publishing content.
- Co-authoried Excel 2010 in Simple Steps. ISBN: 0-27-373613-2